Bernardo Mondragon Brozon

Software Developer

Details

Mexico City, Mexico

- +52 1 55 3559 2033
- +1 571 626 122

bmondragonbrozon@gmail.com

DATE OF BIRTH

Mexican 16-12-199

Links

https://github.com/BernardoMB



A https://independent.academia.edu/BernardoMondragón

Skills

- Analytical and flexible approach to problem solving
- Able to deal with complex maths and technical problems

Programming

Languages: R, Python, Javascript, TypeScript, C#, DAX, SQL, Java, Visual Basic, Objective C, RMarkdown, Bookdown, MatLab, Maple, LaTeX, HTML5, CSS

Fameworks: Spark, Angular, NodeJS, Express, NestJS, ReactJS, Redux, Blazor Server, Blazor WebApp, .Net Framework, .Net, ASP.NET, ASP.NET MVC, Polymer, TypeORM, Angular Material, Bootstrap, Syncfusion. Ext.Net. D3 IS. lest, Cypress

Databases: Cosmos DB, SQL Server, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MySQL, Microsoft Access

Cloud: Microsoft Azure, Databricks, Power BI, Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud, Azure DevOps, Heroku, Netlify, Twilio, SendGrid, Stripe, DHL, FedEx, Cypress, Slack, Redis

Languages

English (native)

Spanish (native)

Profile

I am a actuary with vast experience in Software Development and with a demonstrated history of working in the information services industry.

Skilled in Software Development, Data Science, Business Intelligence, Insurance Theory, Risk Management, and Product Development. Strong analytical professional with a Bachelor's Degree In Actuarial Science focused in Applied Mathematics to assess risk in insurance, finance and other industries and professions.

Education

Bachelor's in Actuarial Science AUG 2013 - AUG 2018

Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo de México (ITAM)

Applied mathematics and statistical methods to assess risk in insurance, finance and other industries and professions.

Diplomat in Insurance Theory OCT 2021 - FEB 2022

Solvency II Diploma NOV 2020 - FEB 2021

Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM)

Experience

Senior Developer JAN 2021 - PRESENT

Toyota Material Handling, Columbus IN

Developed an IT Asset Management strategy, aligning with financial processes and governance controls. Strengthened stakeholder trust through reporting and consulting.

Built a pricing tool for discounts based on marketing data. Streamlined customer request approvals and generated thousands of quotes.

Senior Full-Stack Developer JAN 2021 - MARCH 2024

OSSE, Washington DC

Developed OSSE's School Health Profile portal to support the Healthy Schools Act of 2010. Improved health conditions for 251 schools, positively impacting 93,843+ students. Generated detailed reports to inform OSSE, the Mayor, DC Council, and the Healthy Youth and Schools Commission on school health compliance.

Managed and monitored 200,000+ cases, enhancing student transportation for 93,843+ students. Ensured timely notifications for schools, parents, and emergency services regarding incidents. Assisted the Parent Resource Center, Dispatch teams, and investigators in case assessments.

Data Scientist DEC 2022 - MARCH 2024

One Auction View, Redlands CA

Processed, cleaned, and analyzed millions of records from the automotive industry. Created powerful dashboards that provided valuable insights for lenders and financial institutions. Assisted 20+ dealerships in the U.S. with decision-making for restocking and trend analysis, maximizing profits through segmentation, forecasting, and data modeling.

Full-stack Developer NOV 2020 - DEC 2022

Zurich Insurance Company, Mexico City

.Net development of sureties administration system in Zurich North América.

Financial Analysis, Risk Underwriting Automation and Account Management.

Support and development of underwriting app for international policies; from data capture to issuance. Technologies used: .Net, Blazor, Entity Framework, SQL Server, Git, Bitbucket, Jira, Jfrog, Redis, Dynatrace Jenkins, Linux VMs, Figma.

CoFounder JAN 2019 - JAN 2022

Kalyptio.com, Mexico City

Design and execute strategic processes to deliver best quality software for our clients.

I monitor that industry standards are met according to best coding practices.

I have satisfied over 30+ customers providing them with software that suits their needs.

Lead Developer JAN 2013 - DEC 2018

Neolinx de México SA. de CV., Mexico City

Successfully developed and implemented software solutions to manipulate and analyse data generated by the telecommunication industry for Mexico's Attorney-General's Office (PGR) and Mexico's Center of Investigation and Nation Security (CISEN).

Helped saving hundreds of lives and preventing thousands of crimes.

Successfully parsed over 700 million CDR (call detail registries) from different random formats.

Producer JAN 2012 - AUG 2013

Ecorise Youth Innovations NPO, Austin TX

Pedagogue, designer, and producer of educational interactive and animated content.

Animated over 40 educational video lectures for hundreads of students coursing elementary school.

Freelance

Instructor JAN 2019 - PRESENT

Mexico City

I teach online courses and create tutorials for students who want to get started in the software development industry.

I have taught hundreds of hours of programing lectures